Internal network abuse matters because healthcare applications often handle ePHI,
user identity, clinical workflows, patient portals, APIs, and integrations.
Teams should look for this issue in user-facing features, administrative tools,
background jobs, and service-to-service communication.
Cloud metadata exploitation matters because healthcare applications often handle ePHI,
user identity, clinical workflows, patient portals, APIs, and integrations.
Teams should look for this issue in user-facing features, administrative tools,
background jobs, and service-to-service communication.
Trust boundary violations matters because healthcare applications often handle ePHI,
user identity, clinical workflows, patient portals, APIs, and integrations.
Teams should look for this issue in user-facing features, administrative tools,
background jobs, and service-to-service communication.
Network segmentation, URL allowlists, and egress filtering help reduce SSRF risk.
Selected HIPAA mappings for this topic include Section 164.312(a)(1) - Access control;
Section 164.312(e)(1) - Transmission security;
Section 164.308(a)(1)(ii)(B) - Risk management.